Windmuller, John P. Records /3028
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
John P. Windmuller Records
1951-1964
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Windmuller, John P.
/3028
2 cubic feet
2 linear ft.
Records (documents).
John P. Windmuller's papers regarding the ILR School International Relations Department.
3073885
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183> kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center
Compiled by:
R. Miles, January 12, 2016
EAD encoding:
Randall Miles, January 14, 2016
Biographical / Historical
John P. Windmuller (December 4, 1923 - December 2, 2003) was Professor of Industrial and Labor Relations at Cornell University's New York State School of Industrial and Labor Relations.
A graduate of the University of Illinois (BA, 1948) and Cornell University's ILR School (PhD, 1951), Windmuller joined the Cornell University faculty in 1951. He was appointed the Martin P. Catherwood Professor of Industrial and Labor Relations in 1983. He was named professor emeritus in 1987.
An expert in the study of international and comparative labor relations, Windmuller authored many books and reports on the topic, among them Collective Bargaining in Industrial Market Economies: A Reappraisal (ILO, 1987) and Labor Relations in the Netherlands (Ithaca: Cornell, 1969). With Alan Gladstone, he edited Employer Associations and Industrial Relations: A Comparative Study (New York: Oxford, 1984).
See the Cornell University Faculty Memorial Statement for Professor John Windmuller
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
Related Materials
Related Collections: /4046: ILR School Historical School Documents /4065: John P. Windmuller Additional Papers /4158: John P. Windmuller Additional Papers 5033: International Communist Front Organizations Monthly Publications and Miscellaneous Publications 5272: International Confederation of Free Trade Unions Asian Regional Organization Records 5586m: International Trade Secretariats Miscellaneous Documents 5725: International Communist Front Organization Additional Publications
International labor activities.; Windmuller, John P.; New York State School of Industrial and Labor Relations --Faculty.
3073885
- Turkish Program - Ford (Hall), 1961 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Turkish Program - Frank Miller, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Turkish Program - General, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Turkish Program - IIE (Oetjens), 1961 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Turkish Program - Proposal to Ford, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Turkish Program, 1959-1960 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Turkish Program, 1958 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Turkish Report, 1958 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Turkish Program, 1957 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Indonesian Program, 1959 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- International Institute Correspondence, 1951 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- International Institute - Information, 1951 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- International Institute - Memos, 1953 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Annual Report Inst. Of International ILR, 1954 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- International Institute Job Candidates, 1964 (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Conference - Distribution and Promotion, 1954 (Box 1, Folder 16)
- A, 1953 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- B, 1953 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- C, 1953 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- D, 1953 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- E, 1953 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- F, 1953 (Box 2, Folder 6)
- G, 1953 (Box 2, Folder 7)
- H, 1953 (Box 2, Folder 8)
- I, 1953 (Box 2, Folder 9)
- J, 1953 (Box 2, Folder 10)
- K, 1953 (Box 2, Folder 11)
- L, 1954 (Box 2, Folder 12)
- M, 1953 (Box 2, Folder 13)
- N, 1953 (Box 2, Folder 14)
- O, 1953 (Box 2, Folder 15)
- P, 1953 (Box 2, Folder 16)
- Q, 1953 (Box 2, Folder 17)
- R, 1953 (Box 2, Folder 18)
- S, 1953 (Box 2, Folder 19)
- T, 1953 (Box 2, Folder 20)
- V, 1953 (Box 2, Folder 21)
- W, 1953 (Box 2, Folder 22)
- XYZ, 1953 (Box 2, Folder 23)